Thomas Christopher Zichko

Cocoa, FL 32926

(931) 248-4610

chriszichkocoding@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/chris-zichko-264b25217/

https://zichkoding.github.io/

https://github.com/ZichKoding

Career Summary

Passionate and proud Full-Stack Software Developer going on two years of experience in Frontend and one year experience with Backend, while leveraging my previous experiences outside of the technology field in maintenance and military to help create a more efficient, captivating, and simple user experience using Python 3+, JavaScript ES6+, Node.js, Sequelize, Express.js, Handlebars, Jest, CSS3, Bootstrap, jQuery, HTML5, GitHub, Heroku, MySQL, Kivy 2.0+, and WordPress. I have on my own received a certificate in Scientific Computing with Python from FreeCodeCamp, and currently working on becoming a certified Full-Stack Software Developer through the University of Central Florida.

Technical Skills

- Python 3+
 - o Kivy 2.0+
- JavaScript ES6+
 - o jQuery
 - o Node.js
 - o Express.js
 - o Jest
 - Sequelize
 - o Bcrypt.js
- CSS3
 - o Bootstrap
- HTML5
- Handlebars

- Git
- Heroku

Experience

May 2021 - PRESENT

Edpresso | **Educative.io**, **Remote** - Technical Documentation Writer

- Creating interactive technical documents for specific modules in Python for the students at Edpresso|Educative
- The assigned modules have been created swiftly and correctly with little to no editing from their editorial staff.
- Was recruited for this position and recruited to be on their podcast for one of the best contributors.

February 2021 - PRESENT

ZichKoding, Cocoa, FL – Owner/Software Developer

- Creating and maintaining apps for business owners for a tool for them to use between the business owner and the customers.
- Two of the main applications I have built with this company are a Piano Chord Progression app for Taylor Academy of Music and La Fetching Pooch's website. Still under contract to maintain and update where needed for both companies.

October 2019 - PRESENT

NRT Methodologies, Cape Canaveral Air Force Station, FL - Lead Plant Operator/Site Manager

- Originally started as an assistant but the manager left, and I stepped in as a temporary
 Site Manager and have several documentations that the site looks and operates better
 than it has in years. This has led to an increase in budget to greatly improve the site for
 longevity.
- Ensure functionality of the SLC29 assets to enable training, technical and intelligence opportunities through their operation.
- Regular maintenance and evaluation of the component performance of the chemical feed pumps, pressure transmitters, temperature transmitters, reactors, distillation columns, base scrubbers, temperature control units, vacuum pumps, piping, rotary evaporators, and spray dryer to name a few on the Chemical Synthesis Skids.
- Operating, diagnosing issues, and fixing issues that arise on the Chemical Synthesis Skids through Supervisory Control and Data Acquisition (SCADA) system.

United States Marine Corps, Knoxville, TN – Non-Commissioned Officer/Combat Engineer/Squad Leader

- Received special recognition from several major training exercises including ITX at Twenty-Nine Palms, CA, and Northern Strike in Michigan for outstanding leadership abilities.
- Trained Marines with the appropriate skills, knowledge, and abilities to do their duty as Combat Engineers execute their missions and succeed as Combat Engineers in demanding environments.
- Specialized skills in design, construction, maintenance of equipment, and demolition: Buildings, obstacles, radios, generators, motors, rockets, and all types of explosives.

EDUCATION

AUGUST 2015 - JANUARY 2017

Tennessee Tech University, Cookeville, TN

• Completed coursework towards a Bachelor of Art in Physics

MAY 2015 - AUGUST 2015

Military Occupation School, Camp Lejeune, NC

Certificate in Engineering from the United States Marine Corps

AUGUST 2020 - PRESENT

Freecodecamp.org

- Certificate in Scientific Computing with Python from FreeCodeCamp
- Certificate in Data Analysis with Python (Currently working on)

AUGUST 2021 - February 2022

University of Central Florida, Cocoa, Florida:

Certificate in Full-Stack Web Development from the University of Central Florida